<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>archlinux on Rayan Nakib</title><link>https://nakibrayan2.codeberg.page/tags/archlinux/</link><description>Recent content in archlinux on Rayan Nakib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nakibrayan2.codeberg.page/tags/archlinux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Archlinux Post Install Guide</title><link>https://nakibrayan2.codeberg.page/blog/archlinux-post-install/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nakibrayan2.codeberg.page/blog/archlinux-post-install/</guid><description>1. Install Drivers 1.1 Network/Wireless Check the driver status To check if the driver for your card has been loaded, check the output of the lspci -k or lsusb -v command, depending on if the card is connected by PCI(e) or USB. You should see that some kernel driver is in use, for example:
$ lspci -k 06:00.0 Network controller: Intel Corporation WiFi Link 5100 Subsystem: Intel Corporation WiFi Link 5100 AGN Kernel driver in use: iwlwifi Kernel modules: iwlwifi Note: If the card is a USB device, running dmesg | grep usbcore as root should give something like usbcore: registered new interface driver rtl8187 as output.</description></item><item><title>Archlinux Install Guide With Full Disk Encryption</title><link>https://nakibrayan2.codeberg.page/blog/archlinux-install-guide-full-disk-encryption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nakibrayan2.codeberg.page/blog/archlinux-install-guide-full-disk-encryption/</guid><description>1. Pre installation 1.1 Download the Arch Linux ISO Visit the Download page and acquire the ISO file, and the respective GnuPG signature.
1.2 Verify signature It is recommended to verify the image signature before use, especially when downloading from an HTTP mirror.
On a system with GnuPG installed, you can verify the image signature by downloading the ISO PGP signature under Checksums in the Download page and verifying it with</description></item></channel></rss>